Guillermo Martínez

Hostal de la Pega, 7 Montcada i Reixac 08110, Barcelona

+34 695619727

guillemmartinezconejos@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/guillemmc

I am passionate about creating and developing apps, both mobile and web. I like knowing that thanks to my knowledge I can help ideas become true. That is why since I finished my studies I have focused on software development, and my goal is to continue growing, training, and improving my skills in this field.

I am a curious, cheerful, responsible, and disciplined person. I have experience working in both, teams and solo. Moreover, I count quite a bit of remote working experience. I believe that a good atmosphere in the workplace is the key to be active and motivated, that is why I always try to be in good humor and giving the best of me.

Professional Experience React Native Mid-Level, GooApps (OCT 2020 - FEB 2021) Remote

- Implement apps from scratch until deployed in the stores.
- · Maintenance of existing apps.
- · Reviewing and controlling the quality of the code.
- Meetings with clients to get to know the needs.
- · Backoffice web development to manage the data.

Software Developer, INTERIORVISTA (AUG 2018 - SEP 2019) Barcelona, Spain

When I returned home I came back completely to the front-end team where I was working with the newest technologies, but not for long. After some months they assigned me to the algorithm development team. I started working with C++ and I was doing complete different stuff, but always helping the front-end team if needed.

I have evolved a lot in this company and I have worked in very different roles (and pretty successfully must say), and I think that this fact defines me pretty good. It defines me because of my ability to get used to changes, to learn new technologies and face new challenges. I learned plenty of different things at the university and this company gave me the option to improve my skills on them.

Software Developer, INTERIORVISTA (FEB 2017 - MAR 2018) Remotely, Australia

At one point I realized that my career would need something else and I decided to move to Australia (Gold Coast) to master my English for one year and a half. INTERIORVISTA offered me the awesome opportunity of keeping working together, so I picked up a laptop and I continued working for them from the other side of the world.

My role while I was there changed a little bit, I still was int the front-end development team, but they assigned me one man team as well. I was moved to 3D maintenance. So at that time I was half time doing front-end and the other half working with Unity.

FrontEnd Developer, INTERIORVISTA (JAN 2016 - FEB 2017) Barcelona, Spain

At INTERIORVISTA I started working as a web developer, when I started working the technology used was Angular II but soon we moved to React.js. Working in this role I earned experience in responsible website development and I worked for the first time with Google Analytics.

Working there I learned the importance of GIT and how useful an Agile (we used SCRUM) methodology can be for you team.

FullStack Developer, ESADE Alumni (NOV 2014 - JAN 2016) Barcelona, Spain

In ESADE Alumni I did my internship during the end of my university years. Working there we made use of technologies such as PL/SQL by Oracle, HTML Javascript and CSS.

Education

Diploma of Project Management en Entrepreneur Education, Gold Coast, Australia (2017 - 2018)

Thanks to this diploma I learned the basics on project management, so it gave me the skills to manage and motivate a team if needed in the future.

Multimedia Engineering Degree La Salle (Universidad Ramón Llull) Barcelona, España (2011 - 2016)

At university I learned a lot about IT in all its forms, I learned basics on things such as web development, mobile development, 3D animation and modeling, video games, video editing and visual effects, image and signal processing, communications, music creation, etc.

Other Experience

Cook, Sunshine Village Ski Resort (OCT 2019 - MAR 2020) - Banff, Canada

I was cooking in a kitchen of an Italian restaurant, I do everything in there, form cleaning dishes to cook pasta, pizzas making sandwiches preparing sauces or doing the expo of the kitchen.

Cook, Delaware North (MAR 2018 - MAY 2018) - Gold Coast, Australia

Preparing meals in the cold kitchen.

Chopping + peeling.

Cooking with in huge grills, fryers and ovens.

Curses

React Native: Complete course on Udemy.com about developing mobile apps.

Apps Development: Online course by Google Activate.

CCNA1: La Salle - URL, 2013-2014 (university recognized by CISCO)

3ds MAX level 3 - Animation: La Salle - URL, 2012-2013

Degree Thesis

To develop my degree thesis (and conclude my university studies), I collaborated with the university to develop a mobile app (more exactly for iOs devices). I did not know much about that kind of programming, but my willing to learn and develop a beautiful project made me to ginger up and carry it forward. From that moment I consider myself a self-taught person and I am afraid of nothing.

Languages

Spanish: Native. Catalan: Native.

English: Fluid. Level C2 but not certificated.
French: Basic. Studied at High School.
German: Basic. Initiation course.